This is Adam
Adam has a rather large to do list today,
including completing a spreadsheet for work,
answering some emails and finishing the assignment that is due next week.
He has a very busy day,
yet distractions keep creeping in.
Instead of working on the things he needs to get done,
Adam chooses to watch a video on his laptop.
He says it will only be this one video and then he will get back to work.
But we know that isn't the case.
Adam's phone is buzzing with notifications from
social media alerts to messages from friends.
Constant notifications keep breaking his focus.
His sister is in the next room playing music.
His mum is downstairs talking loudly on the phone.
Cars beep as they drive past his house.
Fed up of the noise,
Adam puts on some headphones and plays some relaxing music.
He then sets up a visual timer on his phone to
make sure he can't access it for the next 25 minutes.
he feels himself gaining control of the situation.
Adam has now been working successfully for a little while.
his spreadsheet is done,
the emails are answered,
and now he is working on his assignment.
With the right tools,
Focus returns.
Thanks to time management techniques,
Adam has ended his day feeling happy and can go to bed with a clear mind.